A Guide to the Papers of the YWCA of Hampton Roads 1910s-1990s
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
The Papers of the YWCA of Hampton Roads 1910s-1990s
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 76
13 Hollinger Boxes and 26 Oversize Boxes.
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift from the Norfolk YWCA, August 2000.
Biographical/Historical Information
The YWCA (Young Women's Christian Association) is the oldest and largest women's membership association. It began in London in 1855, and first came to the U.S. in 1858. Although similar in name, the YWCA has no affiliation with the YMCA. The YWCA was an independent movement that arose out of Women's church groups as a way of making life better for other women. These first YWCA's provided boarding houses, skills training, recreation, and a social environment for single, working women. After World War II, the YWCA's emphasis shifted to the family: mother and children. In 1946, the YWCA adopted an Interracial Charter. Its purpose became the empowerment of women and the elimination of racism.
The YWCA of South Hampton Roads started as housing for working girls in 1893. In 1908, the Phyllis Wheatley Branch of the YWCA of Norfolk began as an association of African American Women. The branch was named after a black woman poet who lived during the time of the Revolutionary War. Another YWCA started in Norfolk in 1911. This chapter had a residence for single women, and offered classes in cooking, stenography, Bible studies, typing, and gymnastics. It also had a cafeteria and a reading room. In 1925, the two branches came together. Then, in the 1950s a Virginia Beach branch was created. Over the years, many splits and mergers have occurred in the YWCA's of Hampton Roads. Throughout their history, the YWCA chapters of Hampton Roads have created many institutions in the community. Camp Owaissa, Camp E.W. Young, and various day camps have provided summer recreation for young girls. The Norfolk YWCA ran a cafeteria on West Freemason for many years. The YWCA has hosted women's shelters including the Phyllis Wheatley House, the Wilkshaw, and undisclosed battered women's shelters.
Other YWCA programs have included the Winners Dinners where women of achievement have been recognized, Y-Prep and Y-Teens for young and adolescent girls, Black History Month, the Women in Crisis Program for victims of domestic violence, the Women in Transition Program to help economically disadvantaged women find employment or gain job skills, and Ladies Day Out workshops and fashion shows.
In addition to these, the YWCA of Hampton Roads has held and continues to hold a wide variety of programs for women of all ages and backgrounds. They offer classes, workshops, and training; fashion and talent shows; retreats; conventions; political events, achievement and award dinners, services and shelter for battered and abused women and children; and a variety of youth programs.
Scope and Content Information
The majority of this collection consists of photos, scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, and loose newspaper clippings. The context of many of the photos and some of the articles is unknown. Also included in this collection are documents relating YWCA facts, history, meeting minutes, activities, correspondence, as well as brochures, booklets, flyers, and similar materials.
Organization
This collection is broken down into the following series: I. Information and History; II. Newspaper Clippings; III. Photos; and IV. Artifacts.
Series I: Information and History. This series contains documents related to YWCA. Information includes YWCA history, facts, and purpose; a 1950 Charter; a guide for participation in the 1960s; a report on financial statements in 1987; an address list; newsletters; membership recruitment guide; meeting minutes; correspondence from 1990-92 and 1996; information, flyers, and invitations for the Annual Winners Dinner 1993-96; Teen Recognition Dinner and Summit 1992-93; Women in Transition; 1960s Ladies Day Out; Black History Month; 1970s events; Annual Report of Residence for the Wilkshaw in 1946; Domestic Violence guides and pamphlets; 1992-93 Legislative Wrap Up; Samaritan House; Tidewater Chapter of the National Organization for Women (NOW); and other documents.
Series II: Newspaper Clippings. This series contains loose newspaper articles and clippings. Topics include pregnancy; women's success stories; racial violence in 1960, YWCA Bible courses; dedication of the Phyllis Wheatley YWCA building; Sunday at the Y program; Obituary of Mrs. Annie Tucker Hitchens; Camp Owaissa; YWCA events; profiles of women; new arrival announcements; and other articles related to the YWCA. Dates of articles range from the 1910s to the 1990s.
Series III: Photos. This series is divided into twelve subseries of photos. Subseries A: Youth Photos; B: Dinners; C: Holidays and Birthdays; D. Women, Staff, and Volunteer Photos; E. Sports and Fitness; F: Events; G: Political; H: Meetings; I: Training, Team Building, Retreats, and Conferences; J: Other Titled Photos; K: Miscellaneous/Dated Slides, Photos, Negatives; and L: Miscellaneous/Undated Slides, Photos, Negatives.
Subseries A: Youth Photos. This subseries contains photos of before and after school programs including Camp Owaissa and Camp E.W. Young; Y-Teens; Y-Nots; Teen Awards; Teen dinners, conventions, and events; school photos, and various photos of children. The dates of these photos range from the 1920s to the 1980s. Several of these photos are of unknown date.
Subseries B: Dinners. This subseries includes photos of various YWCA dinner events including Annual Dinner Meetings and Winners Dinners. The majority of these photos are from 1993 to 1996, with some photos from the 1960s.
Subseries C: Holidays and Birthdays. This subseries includes holiday and birthday photos including Easter events, Christmas parties, and the YWCA 135th Birthday Celebration. The dates of these photos range through the 1980s and 1990s, with some photos of unknown dates. Of note is the picture of Janet Reno at the YWCA Birthday Celebration.
Subseries D: Women, Staff, and Volunteer Photos. This subseries includes photos of individual women such as Sandy Batchelor, Laura or Ann Bowles, Barbara Ciara, Betty Howell, Helen Hazell Moore, and Dr. Lucy Wilson; photos of YWCA Officers, Phyllis Wheatley Staff, and Employees; and photos of Women at Work. The dates of these photos range from the 1960s to the 1990s with several undated photos.
Subseries E: Sports and Fitness. This subseries includes photos of the Red Cross Swimming Class, gym photos, tennis photos, and the Lady Monarchs. Dates range from the 1960s, 1970s, and 1990s.
Subseries F: Events. This subseries includes photos of the Thursday Club, Ladies Day Out, Leisure Hour, Talent and Fashion Shows, and various other YWCA events. Dates of photos range from 1961 to 1996, with several undated photos.
Subseries G: Political. This subseries includes civil rights photos, voter registration 1964, photos of a vigil, and Chuck Robb photos 1982.
Subseries H: Meetings. This subseries includes photos from various meetings including award meetings, membership meetings, and STOP. The majority of these photos are from the 1980s and 1990s, with some from 1967. Other photos are undated. Of particular note are the photos of Virginia Beach Mayor Myera Obendorf at the opening of the Little Neck Road Center.
Subseries I: Training, Team Building, Retreats, and Conferences. This subseries includes photos of the 1965 Va. State Conference, World Fellowship Conference, Leadership and Retreat Photos, "What a Team" slides, workshops and training, and the YWCA Triennial Convention. Dates of photos range from 1965 to 1996 with some undated photos.
Subseries J: Other Titled Photos. This subseries includes group and house photos, Women in Crisis, Church Women United, Diocese of Southern Virginia, photocopies of the YWCA Headquarters, and various other photos. Dates of these photos range from the 1960s to the 1990s. Many photos are not dated or their dates are questionable.
Subseries K: Miscellaneous/Dated Photos. This subseries includes various dated, but untitled photos from the 1960s to the 1990s.
Subseries L: Miscellaneous/Undated Slides, Photos, Negatives. This subseries includes several folders of various slides, photos, and negatives. The dates, places, and contexts of these are unknown.
Series IV: Artifacts. This series consists mainly of scrapbooks. These scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, flyers, photos, and slides. Clippings range in dates from as early as 1919 continue up until the 1990s. Some articles are undated. Topics include YWCA conferences; Camp Owaissa; Ladies Day Out; new YWCA director and officer announcements, retirements, and resignations; various calendar events and meeting schedules; Y-Teens; the Community Chest Drive; "Y" book reviews; dinners and luncheons; speakers; news profiles of women; classes, workshops, and projects; speakers; World Fellowship Week; Open Houses; membership; wedding announcements; YWCA buildings; teen etiquette; the Southeastern Tidewater Opportunity Project (STOP); after school study programs; women's basketball; the YWCA cafeteria; Fashion shows; Tidewater Rape Information Service, emergency services, and battered women's shelter; National Organization for Women (NOW); Black Heritage Awareness Day; Youth Festival; Domestic Violence Awareness Week; and other YWCA activities.
Of particular historical note are the articles on "Business Girls Role in the War" and Women's Role in Defense, School Integration and the U.S. educational system, the Christian Church as a weapon against Communism, Interracial talks on job opportunities, a ban on high heel shoes and short skirts, and a League of Women Voters project to identify barriers that inhibit minority participation in elections.
Contents List
- Information and History
  - YWCA Information and History (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of YWCA (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - YWCA Facts (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charter, March 29, 1950 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - YWCA Certificate of Incorporation (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Statement of Purpose, 1967 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of Phyllis Wheatley Branch Scrapbook and History Information (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - National Initiatives, 1994-1995 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Why Double You? Membership Recruitment Drive Kit (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Membership Recruitment Handbook (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guides for Participation: Study of the YWCA as a Christian Movement, 1964-1967 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - YWCA Program, 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Report on Examination of Financial Statements, June 30, 1987 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Address List (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting Minutes, March, 1981 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Committee Minutes-Finance, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Committee Minutes-Program, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Committee Minutes-Ad. Hoc. L. Robertson, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committee Minutes-Public Relations, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Committee Minutes-Personnel, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Committee Minutes-Membership, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee Minutes-Building and Properties, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Committee Minutes-Executive Committee, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Committee Minutes-Task Force, January-December 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - YWCA Newsletter, 1983 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - YWCA Newsletter, 1990-1992 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Cynthia Kurtz Jackson, June 10, 1996 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - YWCA Annual Meeting, 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - YWCA Annual Meeting, May 15, 1986 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Winners Dinner Information (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Winners Dinner, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Winners Dinner Awards, March 2, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Winners Dinner-Invitations and Programs, 1994 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Winners Dinner-Programs, 1995 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Winners Dinner-Program, 1996 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Winners Dinner, 1996 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Teen Recognition Dinner, November 12, 1992 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 10th Annual Teen Recognition Dinner, November 12, 1992 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1st Annual Teen Summit (I), February 15, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1st Annual Teen Summit (II), February 15, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Women in Transition (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 23)
  - YWCA, 1960s (Ladies Day Out) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Black History Month (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Events, 1970s (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Clara Barton Society and United Way of South Hampton Roads-Cards (congratulations): 1996 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Annual Report of Residence for Year 1946 (photocopies): (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Domestic Violence/Women in Crisis (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "A Guide for Women and Families in Crisis" (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The War at Home: The Military's Problem with Spouse Abuse (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Response-Sexual Assault Support Services (Pamphlet) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sixth Annual Legislative Wrap Up, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 6th Annual Legislative Preview Receptions, December 12, 1992 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 6th Annual Legislative Wrap Up, Tuesday, March 9, 1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Brochure Materials and Photos, 1981 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Samaritan House (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 37)
  - N.O.W. or Never (Tidewater Chapter of N.O.W.), May 1995 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 38)
  - In Celebration of Black History Month, 1994 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Business Writing That Works! (O.D.U.), April 19 and 26, 1995 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous (I) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous (II) (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "By Different Boats: We're All Americans," 1940 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Slide Project, 1992-1993 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Computer Paperwork (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 45)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - PR Efforts/Press Releases (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1910s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1920s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1930s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1940s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1950s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1960s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1970s (I) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1970s (II) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1980s (I) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1980s (II) (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1990s (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Articles-Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Coverage (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Copied Articles: 1919-1920, 1936-1945, 1966, 1982 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hampton Roads Woman-Volume 3, #17, March 6, 1994 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Wall Street Journal-"After 120 years, the Hunton's riches are in its History," February 21, 1995 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Journal and Guide Articles (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Publicity (I) (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Publicity (II) (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Articles, Advertisements, and Promos (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Arch Advocate: Alliance for the Rights of Children, Winter/Spring 1995 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Camp Owaissa Clippings (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Article-March 1998-Envelopes-Post it note) (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook Clippings (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook Article, April 1933 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook Cover and Clippings (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 11)
- Photos
  - Youth Photos
    - Before and After School Program (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Before and After School Program-Westhaven Elementary, 1995 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Camp E.W. Young (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Camp E.W. Young, 1960s (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos, 1920s (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos, 1950s (I) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos, 1950s (II) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos, 1969 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos (I) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos (II) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos (III) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Camp Owaissa Photos (IV) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Camp Owaissa-Group Portraits (I) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Camp Owaissa-Group Portraits (II) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Camp Owaissa-Group Portraits (III) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Camp Owaissa-Group Portraits (IV) (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Camp Owaissa-Sports (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Camp Owaissa-Black and White Photos, 1971 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Summer Camp '83 and Papers Imtestures Staff (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Black and White Teen Photos (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Outstanding Teen Program (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Teen Awards (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Y-Teens, 1960s (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Y-Teen Convention, 1964 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Y-Teen Photos, 1965 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Summer Y-Teen Conference, Guilford College, Greensboro, North Carolina, 1965 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Y-Teen Pajama Party, November 1967 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Y-Teens-Phyllis Wheatley Branch, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Y-Teens (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Y-Teen Group Photos (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Y-Teens Dances (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Y-Nots, Fall 1977 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Maids and Matrons (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Maids and Matrons Party for Service Men (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 34)
    - YWCA Teen Art Show Photos, 1980s (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Teen Art, January 1984 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Teen Dinner, 1984 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 37)
    - YWCA Team-Roanoke, VA and Y-Teen Tea (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Pre-Teen Valentine's Day Party, 1969 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Lott Carey Model City Girls, March 1970 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Booker T. Washington High School Marchers, April 1970 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Children's Photos (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Clown Photo and Fortune Telling Fish (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Photos of Boys Playing Dominoes (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Group Meetings with Junior High School Students (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Children's Play (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Jeremy Hinton (7 mos) swimming (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Racism-It Really Hurts (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Youth Dancing (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Youth Photos, 1970s-1980s (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Youth Photos, 1990s (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Youth Photos-Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dinners
    - Annual Dinner Meeting (Phyllis Wheatley Branch), 1963 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 16)
    - World Fellowship Dinner (Giant Open Air Markets), 1967 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Winners Dinner Reception, 1993 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Dinners, 1993 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Winners Dinner Photos, 1994 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Annual Dinner, 1994 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Awards Photos, 1994, 1995 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Winners Dinner Reception, 1995 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Winners Reception, March, 1995 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Winners Dinner, 1995 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Winners Dinner Reception, 1996 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Winners Awards Dinner, 1996 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Winners Dinner, 1996 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Annual Dinner and Tennis Tournament, July 1996 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Winners Dinner Reception, 1998 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Winners Dinner, 1998 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 6)
    - YWCA Winners Dinner, 1999 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Winners Dinner-Black and White Photos (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Response Banquet (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Women's Prayer Breakfast at Quality Inn-Lake Wright, Norfolk (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Black and White Dinner Photos (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Parties and Dinners-Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Holidays and Birthdays
    - 135th Birthday Celebration, Washington D.C., 1994 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Birthday Party (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Mall Photos (Easter Bunny) (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Easter Basket Photos (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Phyllis Wheatley Staff Christmas Party (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Christmas Party Photos, 1981-1982 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Christmas Photos, 1990s (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Shelter Christmas Party, 1994 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Response Christmas Photos 1997 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Christmas (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Christmas Photos (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Holiday Photos (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Going Away Party (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Women, Staff, and Volunteer Photos
    - Sandy Batchleor Photos (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Laura (or Ann Bowles?)-Photos and Negatives (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Barbara Ciara Photo and Negative (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Betty Howell Photo (black and white) (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Helen Hazell Moore (black and white) (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 5)
    - CDR Cathy L. Rearden (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Portrait Photo-Dr. Lucy Wilson (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 7)
    - HE Society-YW Layout-Officers YWCA Board of Management-Photo, February 18, 1950 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 8)
    - HE Women (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Phyllis Wheatley Branch Photos, 1960s (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Phyllis Wheatley Branch Photos, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Phyllis Wheatley Photos (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Phyllis Wheatley Branch-Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 13)
    - TRIS-Tidewater Rape Information Services (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Employee Photos, 1980s-1990s (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Photos-Administration (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Staff Trio (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Staff/Volunteer Photos (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Staff/Volunteer Photos-Black and White (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Volunteers-Men (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Shopping at Nordstrom (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Photos of People (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Women at Work Photos (Dentist, Judge, Scientist) (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 23)